Finding Aid for Arthur H. Vandenberg Papers, 1884-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sound Recordings
  - Sound tape reel
    - Senator Arthur Hendrick Vanderberg replies to recorded statements by President Franklin Roosevelt, 1936, 1 reel-to-reel audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 7 inches (Box 1)
      - [Part 1], [86746-SR-1-1]; (Senator Arthur Hendrick Vanderberg plays recorded statements made by Franklin Delano Roosevelt and comments on issues raised. Recorded in form of debate.)
(18) - 1/13/32 - Former Gov. Green says he regrets appointment of Vandenberg while on his way home from funeral for Rep. Joe Fordney, whom he should have appointed, he says. Some think Green will run against AHV in 1934. Green says AHV appointment, biggest mistake he made.
(29) - 2/28/32 - public statement on prohibition.
(32) - 7/24/31 to 2/29/32 - chronology, handwritten, of the "Banking Bill"
(35) - 2/29/32 dateline - Opposes $132,500,000 Federal highway construction bill. 13 states, such as Michigan, pay 65% and receive 33%.
(38) - AHV begins effort, defeated though, to give H.H. power to reorganize executive agencies - as an "economy" move.
(44) - "The Gravest Speech" - AHV typed note. On Sen. Logan of Kentucky, opposition to Resolution for disaster relief by Sen. Black (Ala.)
(47) -- "The Menace of 'The Morning Hour'" - AHV note - regarding minor unanimous consent bills. Notes irony that Senate worked two weeks to cut 5 million dollars from Interior bill and in a moment, virtually unnoticed, passed bill to give California 6 million dollars plus million in Civil War claims.
(48) -- "Bad Parliamentary Manners" - regarding Joe T. Robinson's interruptions on Senate floor. "He is a parliamentary law unto himself." Dominant personality - generally beloved "No finer man ever sat in the Senate."
(p. 53) & several preceding. AHV mentioned as keynoter for GOP convention.
(p. 5) AHV Note -- "Postscript to the Parker Case" - that nomination is now inadvisable. (AHV had cast deciding vote against Notes recent 5/4 S.C. decision regarding Tex primaries. Says problem would been 4/5 against Negroes if Parker had been on Court.
(p. 69) - Philippine speech
(p. 79) - AHV Note: "The Bonus Expeditionary Force" AHV voted against bill for present cash payment - Senate defeated bill decisively - impressed by Veto consideration.
(p. 81) 7/21/32 - H.H. thank you note to AHV
(p. 85) H.H. letter to AHV thanking AHV for high praise of acceptance speech.
(p. 88) - "Cp Speeches for Hoover-Curtis, Aug-Nov. 1932" - Says traveled 9000 miles in Michigan during cp Also spoke in Ft. Wayne, Chicago, Wash. D.C., Duluth, Minn. Lists 25 Mich. cities.
(p. 91) - 11/17/32 - H.H. thank you note to AHV
Volume V - Fall 1932 - July 1933 (actually Dec.)
Much on FDR's emergency proposals
(pp. 12-14) - front and back - AHV long essay supporting St. Lawrence Seaway - c. Dec. 1932. Big concern is economic benefit to Mich. and mid-west. Governor Comstock, blaming Ford, declares 7-day Bank holiday (SB p. 43)
AHV note - 8 typewritten pages on the Bank Holiday - Feb 9/28, 1933 AHV let Couzens solely sponsor resolution. Piqued but more interested in results. (p. 33-36)
AHV speech text (newspaper) on Nat'l Bank Deposit Insurance 2/26/33 (?) (SB p. 39)
(p. 41) - Begin FDR
(p. 75) - AHV NOTE - May 24, 1933 -- "The Travesty of an Impeachment Trial by the Senate" - Prefers taking impeachment trials from Senate, giving to jury of 12 senators who take testimony and report findings and recommendations with full senate being a mere court of review (p. 75)
(pp. 91-92) - AHV opposes FDR - Democratic proposal to allow Gov. of Hawaii appointee to be non-Hawaiian. AHV succeeded. Criticized move to "carpetbagging."
June 26, 1933 (Newspaper date.) Text (at least most of it) of AHV speech in GR to advertising (?) Federation of America.--A comment of some length, essentially positive on FDR and his new programs. Early attitude toward New Deal.
Volume VI, Jan. 3, 1934 - thru June 1934
(p. 5b) - AHV Note on House accepted resolution, sponsored by FDR men, to prevent debate & amendment (except from Appr. Com.) of appropriation bills during this session. AHV alarmed, calls it dictatorship. Notes Exec absorption, Legis powers.
(p. 22) - Feb. 1 & 2, 1934 - AHV speech on St. Lawrence Treaty
(p. 40) - AHV Note c. Mar. 25, 1934. AHV saw Gompers quote by statue on Mass. Ave. & sent to Pres. In midst of labor-management struggle.
(p. 39) - MH McIntyre, Asst. to Pres., thanks from FDR to AHV.
(p. 45) - AHV-Nye sponsor resolution for investigating Committee (Bd. of Inquiry)
(p. 46) - AHV had served on War Policies Commission, 1931-32, which had recommended that following any declaration of war, individual and corporate incomes be taxed 95% of all that above previous 3 yr. average... [Quoted on p. 46] Legion first proposed AFL favors. Newspaper story summarys (p. 46) Jay Hayden intro into CR by PHV.
(p. 49b) - Pursuant to the resolution, Nye committee appointed by VP: Nye, Pope, Bone, Clark, Shepherd, Barbour, Vandenberg.
(p. 51b) - Washington Post (c. Apr. 15, 1934) - credits AHV as author of Bank insurance.
(p. 62) - AHV article--"Demonetizing War," Weekly Magazine Section, Christian Science Monitor, May 16, 1934, pp. 1, 2.
(p. 63) - opposes electoral college constitutional amendment. Senate sp. Because (1) encourage multiple parties, (2) minority presidents.
(p. 64b) - (& early in this scrapbook) AHV opposes Tariff bill of FDR.
(p. 64b & 65) - AHV Senate Speech opposing FDR tariff bill.
(pp. 79-80) - Jay G. Hayden [Det. News 6/17/34] reviews AHV's first 6 years in Senate: most complimentary.
(p. 86) - AHV, "How We Can Bankrupt the God of War" Liberty, Sept. 1, 1934. 3 p. article very similar to CSM (above) on upcoming Nye investigation.
Volume VII, - Nov. 1934 - to Nov. 1935
No summary page at beginning of this vol.
(p. 3) - Mich. also elected a Repub. Governor
Who helped whom? -JA.
(p. 4) - AHV letter to Chase Mellen, Jr. on health & needs of Republican Party - printed in Herald Trib (?) Long! - numerous remarks on liberalism, Lincoln liberalism, true liberalism, Republican liberalism, etc.
(p. 6) - Mrs. AHV appendicitis on New Years Eve. Has operation in Washington by GB physician - flew in for it.
(p. 10) - AHV - CR sp. and debate on his World Court Reservation
(p. 12) - AHV speech delivered to Nat'l Press Club Jan. 26, 1935.
(p. 15) - Feb. 5 AHV speech on $5b approp. bill. Read it in speeches box.
[Much in this vol on AHV as '36 pres. possibility]
(p. 17) - Feb. 4, 1935 - AHV letter (in newspaper) to young Republican explaining AHV Support of World Court
(p. 18) - Ray Tucker, "Marked Man." Colliers, March 9, 1935 pp. 26, 38. Notes AHV darkhorse. Generally favorable, but not at all fulsome.
(p. 31) - AHV typed note "Unwritten History" - "Breaking the Anti-War-Profits Deadlock" c. April 3, 1935 - Says FDR tried butt in on inq. with a Baruch Commission -unsuccessful - Drive to support Nye Com. - Main story here is AHV's effort to persuade Rep. McSwain to amend his House Bill to include a revenue raising point so Senate could include excess war profits provision. Otherwise, whole Nye effort maybe down drain. McSwain agreed.
(p. 34) -- "The Most Thrilling Gridiron Dinner Episode" (Apr. 13, 1935) - ovation for Finnish Ambassador - Finland paid Debt.
(p. 44) - AHV voted against Wagner Act AFL Pres. says labor won't forget.
(p. 46) - AHV note "A Bonus Veto Side-Light". AHV recounts how a paragraph he suggested was included verbatim in FDR's in-person veto message: The point--inflation resulting from Patman bill would aid able vet at expense of disabled vet on fixed income.
(p. 47) - Barbara Vandenberg Knight divorce (also p. 57)
(p. 60-61) - AHV Note: on Huey Long's 15-1/2 hr. filibuster without real relief like usual (June 12-13, 1935). Admiring. "Huey Long's Filibuster and the new "Young Turks"--5 fresh Demos who frustrate HL.
(p. 62) - AHV speech (np. text) on Court issue - radio NBC See speech box June 20, 1935.
(p. 70b) - Np text of AHV radio talk on FDR tax program. Perhaps same as Aug. 14, 1935 in speech box.
(p. 82) - Betty (Elizabeth) Vandenberg robbed in GR
(p. 94) - to London - vacation, Dateline Oct. 10. Cut vacation mo. short
(p. 96) - Letter from E (?) A (?) Mosre regarding Henry Ford's proffered support of AHV for Pres. U.S.
(p. 101) - Nov. '34 Mich. election returns by county
Volume VIII, Jan. 1936 -
(p. 7) - Dateline Dec. 17, 1935? to NYT. AHV statement opposing Townsend Plan. A Repub. running for Congress and who won special election (AHV for him) was for Townsend.
(p. 7b) - np. article shows AHV most of time voted against FDR, as cf. Borah, Dickinson, McNary --
- see better, more complete list p. 18b -Detroit News Jan 12, 1936.
(p. 23) - AHV note: "Monday, Jan. 27,1936"
(p. 22) - Don Wharton, "Yes and No Man", Today Jan. 1936 notes AHV's "drinking is moderate"
(p. 7) - Sinclair Lewis (on boat) invited AHV to "Come up and have a drink with us"
(p. 10) - Sinclair Lewis on country editors and "It Can't Happen Here"
(p. 30) - Astrology interpretation of Vandenberg and Landon
(p. 41) - Herblock cartoon --
- AHV plays the silent, non-committal, disinterested role in Presidential contest
(p. 43) - Lippmann column on AHV Lincoln Day Speech
(p. 47) - AHV note: on little Gridiron Dinner "Saturday Night, Feb. 29, 1935"
(p. 49) - Krock column - Remarks AHV would prefer 1940 to 1936 nomination.
(p. 51) - Np. text for S. Court radio address
(p. 57) - Lawrence Sullivan, "Cagey Mr. Vandenberg" Farm Journal, Apr. 1936
(p. 59) - AHV wins Florida Canal fight - FDR was doing it without authorization from Congress.
(p. 67) - CSM writer credits AHV with saving 2-party system. Says AHV is FDR's "effective opposition"
(p. 84) - May 2, 1936 - Sat. Eve. Post AHV "The Gang's All Here!" on patronage and FDR Administration
(p. 87) - AHV Note: "The Grant Club"
(p. 88) - "Is the Republic Slipping?" Redbook, June 1936. anti New Deal broadside
(p. 103) - Krock column
(p. 106) - AHV will introduce Cousti amendment to give President power of item veto in appropriation bills. Say - only way get economy. (appears in C.R. p. 107)
(p. 118) - AHV note (14 pages): "The Inside Story of the Republican National Convention at Cleveland"
(p. 142) - AHV "Hash by the Billion! Wanted: A Tax-Saving Diet" Saturday Evening Post, Aug. 29, 1936 p. 10 plugs item veto
(p. 148) - Items regarding AHV use on radio of FDR record
(p. 155) - AHV, "Tariff Protection: An American Necessity" The Forum n.d. (5B VIII, p. 155)
(p. 156) - AHV, "The Republican Indictment" Fortune n.d. (part) symposium - articles also by R.G. Tugvell and E.T. Weir [National Steel Corporation chairmen] (last two not included here).
(p. 156) - Thanks telegram from FDR on re-election
(p. 159) - Editorial in "Washington D.C. Broadcasting" on AHV radio speech using FDR voice, Nov. 1, 1936
Volume IX, Jan. 1937-
(2B) -- "V. asks 'War Quarantine'" New York Times dateline 12/27/36 (?)
(7B) - Dateline Jan. 31, 1937 New York Times - 4 senators seek rigid cash-carry prov.
(13) - article AHV, "How Dead is the GOP?" Saturday Evening Post 2/27/37
(15) - Several CR pages on Reciprocal Trade debate
(17) - Mar. 1, 1937 several Congressional Record pages on Neutrality debate - objects to presidential discretion provisions
(21) - Sit Down Strikes. Favors profit sharing. also (p. 24)
(22) - Child Labor Amendment
(32) - article AHV "The $47,000,000,000 Blight" Saturday Evening Post, Apr. 24, 1937.
(33B) - Neutrality-final - objects to expanded Presidential discretion provisions which come back from Conference Committee. Congressional Record
(62b) - Opposes leasing 6 ships to Brazil for training purposes
(65B) - Abridged text, no date, of VFW speech
(68-75) - AHV Diary Notes
(69) - 1/8/37 Note: turns down Lucky Strike offer
(69) - 1/20/37 Note on Mary?
(69) - 1/23/37 Note minority's plan to use teams of experts in order to get good, effective criticism, improvements; e.g. Soc. Security
(69) - 1/28/37 Note on declining invitation to Russian Embassy dinner
(69) - 2/l/37 draws first full check since 4/l/33. Voluntary in 1933 "Econ. Act" cut federal salaries 15%
(69) - 2/2/38 Note on GM strike in Michigan - against compromise with trespassers
(69) - 2/5/37 Note regarding note by Beaverbrook Mrs. AHV in Arizona for health
(69) - 2/6/37 Note on FDR message regarding Supreme Court plan. Says first time bill ever directly introduced by President: message, letter from Attorney Gen., bill draft, and other papers referred to Judiciary Committee. Notes: H. Hoover wants to be involved; efforts to keep him quiet.
(69) - 2/12/37 Letter from FDR regarding AHV and P. Brown offer to help in GM strike.
(69) - 3/2/37 Note on his radio speech against FDR Court plan; also on his attitude toward Wheeler counter plan.. Joe Alsop a co-conspirator.
(69) - 3/3/37 Passage of neutrality act
(69) - 3/20/37 rues failure of Republicans in Appropriation Comm. to oppose Administration bills
(69) - 4/2/37 Note on his speech blaming FDR for labor probleMS9 strike
(69) - 4/4/37 Farewell lunch for German Ambassador Hans Luther
(69) - 4/15/37 Problems of being accurately reported in press
I
(69) - 5/9/37 More on Supreme Court, FDR's attitude toward NY Court. FDR wants similar relationship with USSC zapped
(69) - 5/13/37 AHV wants Round Robin regarding Court bill; (May 18 note)
(69) - 6/20/37 Steel strike in Ohio. "Revolutionary John - Lewis"
(69) - 6/31/37 His child labor amendment
(75B) - AHV, "The Biography of an undelivered Speech" Saturday Evening Post, Oct. 9, 1937. on Court Pack 80,000 words, perhaps 16 hrs. to deliver
(77) - n.d. Comment on FDR Chicago speech
Volume X, Oct. 1937 - Sept. 1938
[Several cartoons, much n.p. story, & comment on AHV & Party coalition]
(p. 14) - 12/?/37 AHV Note: "The way Communists Operate" -- discusses the tarring Daily Worker gives him - linking Nazis to him etc.
(p. 21) - Beverly Smith "GR Boy Makes Good"
(p. 23) -- "The Truth About the Coalition Manifesto" someone released it to the press - AHV suspects McNary
(p. 25) - dateline 12/22/37 AHV criticizes letters (an exchange of both FDR and Landon. Nix hint of entangling alliance
(p. 26) - np -AHV letter to Detroit group pro-China-Head, Nora Dyron. AHV says nix first step unless ready for last step
(p. 27) - Congressional Record - item veto: AHV-FDR correspondence
(p. 52 & proceeds for several pages): Much on Government Reorganization Bill - AHV hostile, at least in part
(p. 53) - says FDR should renounce a 3rd term
[Joe T. Robinson died July 1937. According to Beverly Smith "GR Boy Makes Good" -- "The Court bill collapsed."]
(p. 58) - Super Navy Bill debate - Congressional Record [12/31/36 all naval limitation treaties expired]
(p. 59) - more on navy bill - Congressional Record (apparently 4/2/38) AHV favors air over sea power; but says is an inexpert opinion
Reapportionment
(p. 62) - more on Naval Bill
(p. 66) - AHV "United We Stand--" Saturday Evening Post 4/28/38 -on coalition for 1940
(p. 84B) - 8/28/38 dateline "V urges Sp Rebirth as America's Need" address dedicating new auditorium: of 7th Day Adventists -Grand Ledge
(p. 85) - Picture in swimming suit sitting at typewriter
(p. 86B) - Sees FDR's purge effort as indication wants "American dictatorship, American style" i.e. with Legislative and Judicial branches packed.
Volume XI, Oct. 1938 - Aug. 1939
(p. 5B) - Letter from Landon regarding 1936 VP nomination 8
(p. 11) - AHV Amer Mag article on profit sharing, Oct. 1938
(p. 13B) - Trade treaty, lowering rate of duty on furniture (affecting Grand Rapids criticized by AHV -np.)
(p. 15) - AHV note: Nov. 27, 1938
(p. 19B) - AHV opposes changing Neutrality Law to let President name an aggressor - n.p. act by G. Gould Lincoln notes oceans insulate
(p. 30B) - Since Murphy recently defeated for Governor of Mich. AHV will vote against confirm as Attorney General - Congressional Record
1939
(p. 35) - Alsop & Kintner Life article, Feb. 9, 1939
(p. 36) - AHV note: "The 'Smear' Campaign" - press rumor regarding AHV-Mrs. V divorce - calls Pearson & Pellet Allen "the two jackals of American journalism" Picture of Mitzi Sims and British Embassy J. Hoche's wife [linked to AHV]
(p. 38) - AHV article in Factory "I Believe in Profit Sharing" Feb. 1939
(p. 42) - AHV note: 2/23/38 "The Export-Import Bank" -- "I was chiefly interested in getting the job done" - so AHV doesn't (all Jesse Jones gets credit of $100 in limitation on the E. Bank) AHV disturbed because no real limit also, Pres had via E.Q. given $25 in loan to China; also political purpose leaves to Mexico and Haiti
(p. 56) - AHV note: 3/24/39 -- Treas. Secretary Morgenthau & FDR have publicly proposed Social Security alternative advocated by AHV since Jan. 1937. --"full reserve" not recess - no need raise by 50% next yr.--on business & employer
(61B) - picture of AHV jr; much resemblance to the Senator
(90B) - AHV wants 1940 GOP nominee to pledge self to one term
(p. 105) AHV note on FDR's introduction to GB King
(p. 113) Marquis Childs article in newspaper on AHV
(115B-116) - Typed excerpts from editorials regarding AHV for President, one-term pledge etc.
(116 B) - dateline June 16 Newspaper article on FDR's introd. to Br. King and FDR's bitter feeling toward AHV.
(124) - Typed "Additional Editorial Comments on my 1940 Statement"
(129B)- Newspaper on AHV resolution on Japan (also p. 130B. A. Krock column p. 133B)
Volume XII
(p. 1) - Sept. 15, 1939 AHV Note: "The Battle over the Arms Embargo"
(p. 4B) on cover of Time, Oct. 2, 1939
(p. 7) article AHV, "Mr. Roosevelt and the Third-Term Dictatorship" Liberty, Oct. 7, 1939
an eg of AHV, the effective persuader, debater - folksy, personal, clever
(7B) - Newspaper article on Oct. 9, 1939 AHV speech also more on 8, 9
(13) - Dateline Sept. 29. On FDR's "limited national emergency"
(18) - Letter Oct. 21, 1939 from Finland ambassador (?) thanking AHV for remarks in Senate
(24) - "The Arms Embargo Battle" Oct. 27, 1939
- neg. note re: Landon letter to Townsend.
(30) -- "November 30,1939" - on Finland's invasion by Russia
- Mr. & Mrs. Harold Sims - guests at AHV dinner; other
(30B) - Announcement of engagement of Barb V. Knight to John Bailey Jr., son of AHV 1928 opponent -- "The marriage will be Mrs. Knight's third. She was married twice to John Knight, Jr., of Kalamazoo and Grand Rapids. They have a son John Jr., who will be 8 years old on Dec. 6. They were divorced a year ago for the second time" (Newspaper, Nov. 27 dateline)
(40B) - AHV, "The New Deal Must Be Salvaged" The American Mercury Jan. 1940 LXIX - No. 193 PP. 1/10
(42) - AHV, "Gag the Senate and You Gag America" Liberty
1/6/40 - notes cooling of atmosphere in special fall session 1939 on repeal arms embargo - due to Senate spending so much time Sept. 21 to Oct. 27 on matter
- Supreme Court packing 1937
- Reorganization bill
(43B) - 12/30/39 -- Barbara's wedding
(52) - 1/18/40 - AHV introduced resolution in Senate asking President to advise whether S.U. has lived up to 1933 Litvinoff agreements
(52B) - Press comment on AHV letter on Jackson Day dinner to Jim Farley.
(53) - AHV typed note "The Death of Senator Borah" Jan. 28th (who died Jan. 19) and also a "PS Feb. 4th" --disputes that Borah would have supported Dem. Wheeler. Recalls WB offer to nominate AHV at Republican Convention 1940 --AHV refuses any public corrections --He got Borah's Desk (p. 53B - at AHV request)
(54) - picture of Mrs. Harold Sims - why?
(56) -Congressional Record (c. Feb. 1, maybe 1/31) AHV inserts Lippman article (Washington Post, 1/30/40) on American-Japanese Relation - says misunderstood AHV abrogation resolution. Also inserts his letter to Lippman in reply. (letter to W.L. - copy is in letter box)
(59) - picture used in front Private Papers...
(59B) - another Lippman column.
(60) - Lippman reply to AHV Jan. 30 letter. Text is undated, unidentified newspaper clipping.
(62B) - Lippman column on AHV alternative to tariff commission & Hull program
(63) - Lippman on Pres. possibilities - Taft, Dewey, AHV - very negative--AHV
(68) - clipping, n.d. Hull admits S.U. may have violated 1933 pact. But relations not dependent on it, he says.
(83B) - 3/20/40 letter from Finland's Procope
(88) - AHV Congressional Record note on Lippman column (above 62B)
(96B) - Brief thank you note 4/13/40 from Chas Evans Hughes
(102B) - AHV succeeds in killing Tombigbee waterway plan -Miss. & Ala.
(108) - 5/23/40 letter from Farley - says he meant the kind words recently uttered, (in Detroit?)
(118B) - To & from FDR (May 1940) re: AHV request for report War Resources Bd.
(118) - AHV "Shall We Break With Russia?" Liberty June 6, 1940
(121B) - June 1 dateline. First mention Of Willkie
(122) - June 9, 1940 radio speech, "Nat'l. Defense and (FP)" -in Congressional Record appendix [Monday June 10 (Legislative day of Tuesday, May 28), 1940]
(134) - Typed Note "'Inside Stuff' - Real History"
-- Suggested Dewey take #2 spot; would set stage for '44 since AHV only one term
-- also to meet at 11:00 to flip coin
(141) - "The Washington 'Merry Go Round' continues its 100% Record for Mendacity" AHV note
Volume XIII, June 1940 - Dec. 1941
(p. 4) - from Congressional Record - reasons for national votes for H. Stimson
(11) - Congressional Record - conscription speech
(11B) - Congressional Record appendix version Republican Service Men's League Speech.
(14) - Aug. 19 letter from James Farley re: Farley's impending retirement
(19B) - Aug. 31 letter from James Farley re: Farley's impending retirement
(27B) statement (New's Year's wishes?) in Detroit Jewish Union
(37B) - election returns--FDR barely won; Dickinson lost; AHV won 1,003,878 to 906,076. [Only token opposition back in primary.]
(39B) - Vote finals: Willkie carried Mich.!!
(39B) - Pearson & Allen column re: re-election Favorable.
[Begin 1941]
(43B) - AHV interview with Foreign Correspondents - suggests U.S. might guarantee a peace - next day Jan. 2 he seems to correct it reassert previous position. May be very significant.
(46) AHV note on FDR "War-by-Proxy" speech
(48) - AHV, "Shall We Get Rid of the Electoral College" LIBERTY Feb. 1, 1941 -- not for change
(59) AHV note on Lend-Lease "Saturday, Mar. 8, 1941! 7:10 P.M."
(63) - AHV pencil note to Joe Morris. Lend lease appropriation bill "This is the beginning of the change."
(66) - Apr. 17, 1941 AHV note: on conference with Morgenthau & others re: new tax program. AHV says President must announce it and stick his neck out first
(66B) - AHV remarks, Borah (15 months dead) memorial service
(67B-68) AHV, quotes Adm. Land, minimizes British ship losses
(73B) - AHV article "How much For a Billion Dollars" Liberty 6/14/41
(90) - AHV Note Beaverbrook (and National Unity). - Beaverbrook, old AHV friend, expresses concern he and British felt at House 203-202 vote on draft bill. AHV blames Administration approach, Interesting criticisms
(90B) - Oct. 4, 1941 letter from FDR re: lend-lease negotiations
(95B) - from H Hoover 10/29/41
Volume XIV, Dec. 1941-Dec. 1942
(p. 1) -- "Dec. 8, 1941" typed AHV Note
[in AHV, Jr. pp. 16-18]
(2) -- "Dec. 11, 1941" typed AHV Note [in AHV, Jr. p. 18-]
(2B) -- "Dec. 13, 1941" typed AHV Note
(3) - Congressional Record pages [Dec. 9?] mentions Congressional liaison committee with Pres.
(5) - Letter to FDR (Dec. 15) and from (Dec. 27) proposing a Joint Congressional Committee on War Coop - 6 senators & 6 reps. elected by the Houses [Cppsu p. 24-25]
(6) - "Jan. 7, 1942" AHV note [ppsu P. 25]
(10) - "Jan. 27, 1942" AHV note [PPSP p. 28]
(11b) Jan. 29 dateline. (AHV critical) "Pact with Mexico Ratified in Senate" --didn't oppose ratification, but thinks bad bargain
(12b) Resolution and statement on Normandy ship disaster
(13) - Newspaper - AHV proposes item veto
(13B) - AHV, Jr. volunteers for army [something cut out of the page]